vani Jain

IV Year Engineering (IT) Student

L 8871880166

Github

Leetcode

Linkedin

Portfolio

I am an inquisitive tech enthusiast with experience in Java Programming, JDBC, SQL and Python. I have constant desire to grow, learn and explore, and an ability to work independently and collaboratively in a team. I have also been trying to refine my programming skills & enhance my knowledge of Data Structure and Algorithms through certain coding platforms like Leetcode and participation in hackathons.

Education

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) in Information Technology University Institute of Technology, RGPV

2020 - 2024

CGPA:-8.64

12th Grade (Central Board of Secondary Education)

2019-2020

Carmel Convent Sr. Sec. School

Percentage: :- 94.2%

10th Grade (Central Board of Secondary Education)

2017-2018

Carmel Convent Sr. Sec. School

Percentage: :- 93.8%

Projects

Sanjeevani Software (link) Core Java, JSwing, Oracle, JDBC, SQL Developed comprehensive hospital administration software leveraging Core Java, JSwing for GUI, JDBC for with Oracle as RDBMS managed through SQL programming for backend operations. Also, integrated API like BulkSMS and 2Factor to achieve enhanced functionalities.

Smart Home Automation (link)

Python, Raspbian OS

An IOT project created using Raspberry Pi and distance sensors in scripting language Python which senses human presence within the given range and switches on the connected devices as per the code in python with an efficiency of 80%.

Joint E-Library (link)

Figma, HTML and CSS

Designed a Joint E-Library website for easy access to a variety of books by collaboratively working on this multi-person project.

Portfolio Website (link)

HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Crafted a vibrant portfolio website leveraging HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, and JavaScript. The site is live on GitHub, showcasing my work and skills.

Fake News Detection System (link)

Python, Machine Learning

Developed and implemented a Python-based machine learning system to detect fake news, leveraging libraries such as Numpy, Matplotlib, and Pandas and achieved an accuracy of 92% in identifying deceptive articles.

Experience

A2Infotech (Software Developer Trainee)

January, 2023 - March, 2023

Involved in Java application development to create an software for hospital administration called Sanjeevani using the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) model dividing the project into modules.

Webinmaker Pvt. Ltd. (Web Developer Intern)

February, 2022 - March, 2022

Understood the development of websites, designing and architecting solutions to provide quality websites as per the requirement specifications.

Skills & Software

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Libraries & Frameworks: JDBC, Swing, Spring Boot
- Database & Operating Systems: Oracle, Windows, Linux
- Tools & Platform: Git, GitHub, Microsoft Office, IntelliJ, Eclipse, VSCode, PyCharm
- Miscellaneous: Data structures & algorithms, object-oriented programming, strong communication skills with a proficiency in English, and problem-solving

Certifications

Certificate of Completion (Elite) - Programming in Java

2023

NPTEL Online Certification (Swayam)

Certificate of Completion - Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization (3 courses) Imperial College of London (Coursera)

2022

2023

Certificate of Completion - Programming Essentials in Python Cisco Networking Academy